Your sins?
（炯(けい)）罪？
It's about the previous
inspectors' accident.
（如月(きさらぎ)）前任監視官の
事故についてです
（炯）ん… 聞かせてくれ
Please tell me.
Before I became an enforcer,
I was a swimming athlete.
（如月）執行官になる前は
スイミングアスリートでした
I had a boyfriend back then.
当時 私には恋人がいました
I've seen your record.
経歴には目を通している
It said that the two of you
were in a car crash.
君たちが乗っていた車が
事故に遭ったと
It wasn't our fault.
相手の過失でした
Both of our Hues deteriorated
and we were institutionalized.
彼も私も 色相が悪化
施設送りに
But there was no change
in the perpetrator's Psycho-Pass.
なのに 加害者は
サイコパスに変化はなく―
They got off with a fine.
罰金刑を受けただけ
Later, my boyfriend
died in the institution.
その後 施設で 彼は亡くなり―
I was found suitable to be an enforcer
and accepted the post.
私には執行官適性が出て
それを受け入れました
I think I wanted an outlet for my anger.
怒りの矛先が
欲しかったんだと思います
Draw the knives
locked behind your eyelids.
♪～
Reap the lives that grow into shackles.
Even the lost memories that flee
once they're liberated and banished
Are an everlasting cubism.
Cause I know that in a future gone mad,
Even nightmares are peaceful.
RESET, RESET, yeah.
The midnight sun
awakens and turns to a riot.
A gun for a faux-friendly kiss.
A knife for a faux-revolutionary hug.
Get rid of it all, even the frozen chains.
Reality is always outside your head.
In a world seen through bestial eyes,
There is neither darkness nor light.
Draw the knives
locked behind your eyelids.
Reap the lives that grow into shackles.
Even the false memories that flash before
your eyes impatiently and impulsively
Are an everlasting cubism.
～♪
One day, a year ago,
１年前のある日
I found online counseling.
ネットで―
オンラインカウンセリングを
見つけました
Chat with a Counselor
（クリック音）
Open up and keep your Psycho-Pass clear.
I was skeptical, but I still revealed
my frustration and desire for revenge.
（如月）半信半疑のまま―
事故の加害者への不満や
報復を打ち明けました
And then?
（炯）それで？
The same driver caused another accident.
（如月）相手が また
事故を起こしたんです
After a while,
that network sent me instructions
しばらくたった時―
そのネットワークから
私に指示が来ました
to file an investigation request
with their maintenance team.
整備班に検査の要望書を
送るようにと
File a request?
要望書？
"Our official vehicle's engine
sounds strange."
“公用車のエンジン音が
おかしい”と―
A false report.
ウソの報告を上げろと
Then immediately afterwards,
the two previous inspectors...
その直後 前任監視官の２人が…
I was one of the cogs in the machine.
私は歯車の１つだったんです
I got scared, and I've ignored
all instructions since then.
怖くなった私は
それ以来 指示を無視しました
Then, I started getting flowers
すると 死んだ恋人の名で
花が送られてくるようになって
sent in my late boyfriend's name.
A threat?
脅迫か…
Yes.
はい
I realized they were sent by the man we
encountered at the Heaven's Leap facility.
そして
教団施設にいたあの男が―
花を送ったと分かりました
Koichi Azusawa?
梓澤廣一(あずさわこういち)？
He was manipulating me.
あの男に 私は操られていた
What about the original driver?
最初の加害者は どうなった？
They were temporarily quarantined,
（如月）
一時的に隔離されましたが―
but their Hue recovered
and now they live a normal life.
色相も回復し
普通に暮らしています
How do you feel now?
今は どう思っている？
It could have easily
turned out much worse.
（如月）
最悪の事態になる可能性もあった
I'm prepared to accept the consequences.
処罰は覚悟しています
ハァ… 俺が課長に話す
I'll speak to the chief.
Don't tell anyone else yet.
今は まだ誰にも話すな
（エンジン音）
It's running a lot better.
（灼(あらた)）調子よくなったね
No matter how old it gets,
maintenance can bring it back.
（篤志(あつし)）どんなに古びても
メンテナンスで必ずよみがえる
Just like counseling!
カウンセリングみたい
Psychological care and tinkering
with cars do have a lot in common.
確かに メンタルケアと
車いじりは似てるな
With time and effort, a mind can clear,
心も 手間をかければ
クリアになるし
ヘヘッ
or be intentionally broken.
わざと壊すこともできる
（玄関のチャイム）
ん？
It's been a long time, Inspector Shindo.
（輝(あきら)）お久しぶりです 慎導(しんどう)監視官
Akira. I'm glad you came.
輝君 よく来てくれたね
Kei.
（灼）炯君！
（篤志）灼
Arata, go play with Kei.
炯君と遊んでいなさい
OK.
うん
Come on, Kei.
おいで 炯君
Go on.
（輝）ほら
（灼）ううっ
I'm going home.
（灼）うっ
What am I,
俺は 何なんだよ
Dad?
父さん
He's criminally asymptomatic.
（霜月(しもつき)）免罪体質者だったなんて
Akane Tsunemori must have known that.
当然 常守(つねもり) 朱(あかね)も知っていた
She made Shindo an inspector
because of some deal.
何らかの取り引きの結果―
慎導を監視官とした
Setting speculations aside,
（細呂木(ほそろぎ)）
その推測は さておき―
if his inspector suitability falls
below regulation,
監視官適性が規定以下となれば―
he will be dealt with
as per protocol.
通常どおり処理する
No objections, I presume?
異存あるまいね？
No, ma'am.
はい
The problem is Bifrost.
問題は ビフロストだ
My thought is
（霜月）私の考えでは―
that it would have to predate
the Sibyl System in order to function.
シビュラシステム運用以前から
存在しなければ―
成立しえません
You think that's possible?
そんな存在がありうると？
It's a hypothesis.
まだ 仮説です
I'll investigate and report on it.
調査し 報告します
You are a capable and ideal citizen.
（細呂木）
君は 優秀で理想的な市民だな
I know that I'm really quite dull.
退屈な存在にすぎないことは
分かってます
Recently, not necessarily.
近頃は そうとも限らないがね
You endorsed a real troublemaker!
（霜月）なんてやっかいなのを
推薦したんです！
But isn't he capable?
（朱）でも 優秀でしょ？
Those remnants showed up, too.
例の残党も現れて―
You're going around
wrecking everything,
先輩が何でもかんでも潰すから―
and I'm the one taking the fall for it!
こっちが
とばっちり受けるんです！
You make it sound like I did it alone.
（朱）私が１人でやったような
言い方ね
Anyway,
I'll look after our two new inspectors.
とにかく 新人監視官２人は
私が面倒 見ます
You mean...
それって…
The CID is short-handed!
刑事課は人手不足なんです！
We can't afford to lose Shindo now.
今 慎導を失うと 困るんですよ
You want to interview the CID?
（霜月）
刑事課に インタビューですか？
Yes. For a documentary on justice.
（六合塚(くにづか)）ええ 正義についての
ドキュメンタリーです
Don't you feel that justice in Japan
has changed?
この国の正義の変容を
感じませんか？
うーん
Human justice has no value.
人間の正義に価値はない
Is that wrong for a member
of the Public Safety Bureau to say?
なんて 公安局員が言うと
問題ですかね？
What is justice to you, Mika?
美佳(みか)ちゃんにとって 正義とは？
Doubt not God, test not God.
神を疑うなかれ 神を試すなかれ
Sibyl's justice and values
are beyond consideration.
シビュラの正義と価値は
考えるまでもない
Then...
では…
I didn't say no.
（霜月）ダメとは言ってません
Anything for you, Yayoi.
他ならぬ 弥生(やよい)さんの頼みですから
Thank you.
（六合塚）ありがとう
But couldn't you tell me more
about what you're really after?
（霜月）でも―
もうちょっと本音で話してくれても
いいんじゃないですか？
This is for Akane, isn't it?
先輩のためなんでしょ？
フッ
It's not that simple.
そう単純な話ではないわ
You're old friends and in the same unit.
（六合塚）幼なじみで 現場も同じ
Do you think your superiors planned that?
上層部に 何か意図があったと
思いますか？
"Planned"...?
意図って…
We weren't chosen as a pair.
We just both happened to be qualified.
セットで選ばれたわけじゃない
お互いの適性が合っただけです
Arata... Well, he does his best.
灼は…
まあ 一生懸命やってますよ
Speak for yourself.
何だよ 偉そうに
That was a compliment.
褒めただろ
We conjecture Bifrost is an entity that
exploits the Sibyl System's blind spots.
（霜月）ビフロストは―
シビュラシステムの盲点をつく
存在と推測される
Their Crime Coefficients
may not even be measurable.
犯罪係数の計測が可能かも不明
But we know it has
a three-tiered structure.
ただし 三層構造なのは確かね
I've heard them mention "congressmen"
自分が聞いたのは
コングレスマン―
and also "inspectors."
そして
インスペクターという言葉です
Congressmen are the leaders
and inspectors are their subordinates.
（灼）
コングレスマンがトップで―
インスペクターは その部下
Foxes are the lowest level. Civilians
who don't know what they're doing.
狐は末端組織で―
自分が何をやっているか分からない
一般市民
Because they're unaware,
their Crime Coefficients don't increase.
（狡噛(こうがみ)）何をやっているか
分からないから―
犯罪係数も上がらない
A person who unknowingly
makes parts for a gun
（宜野座(ぎのざ)）知らずに
銃の部品を作った人間と―
and the person who fires it
have different Psycho-Passes.
その銃を使う人間じゃ
サイコパスも違う
Why can't we locate them?
（須郷(すごう)）
居場所が特定できない理由は？
As for Koichi Azusawa,
（炯）梓澤廣一という男だが―
his history and lifestyle are so random
that we can't track him down.
経歴も生活もでたらめで―
全く足取りが追えない
He probably lives under someone else's ID.
（灼）恐らく 他人のＩＤで
生活してるんでしょう
Is that even possible?
（花城(はなしろ)）そんなことが可能なの？
Practically speaking,
we have to assume so.
（灼）現実問題
そう考えるしかないんです
I'm getting the picture.
（狡噛）フッ 話が見えてきた
Something has gone wrong with
the blind spot they're hiding in.
そいつらが隠れている盲点に
何らかの問題が生じた
People living in safety only take risks
when that safety is threatened.
安全に暮らす連中が
リスクを取るのは―
その安全が揺らぐ時だけだからな
Which means they'll target
the governor again.
てことは 都知事
（狡噛）また狙われるぞ
（灼）うん
How can you be sure?
なぜ そう言える？
They're not indiscriminate.
（狡噛）無差別な連中じゃない
They targeted her
because they needed her dead.
都知事の死が必要だから
事件の標的にしたんだ
You mean they're still
aiming for recovery?
（霜月）今も挽回を狙っていると
That's right.
ああ そうだ
How do I feel about my cases?
事件で感じること
Seeing people die is really tough.
やっぱり 人の死を見るのは
つらいですね
Even under the Sibyl System,
unfortunate cases exist.
シビュラシステムでも
不運なケースはある
There are always criminals
like those involved in this case.
特に 今回の犯人たちみたいなのは
一定数いる
What do you mean?
みたいなのって…
People who live to harm others.
人を傷つけることが
生きがいの人間だ
There can't be many.
（灼）ごく少数だろ
（炯）フン
Most are normal, right?
大半は普通だよ
We've confirmed heavily armed criminals
separate from Bifrost.
（霜月）ビフロストとは別の―
重火器を持った犯罪者が
確認されてるわ
Peacebreaker remnants?
（狡噛）
ピースブレイカーの残党か？
Yeah, that's right.
（宜野座）ああ そうだ 今は
パスファインダーと名乗ってる
They call themselves "Pathfinders" now.
That's a problem.
やっかいね
Um, what's "Peacebreaker"?
あの… ピースブレイカーって？
I authorize you to view level 3
classified materials. Look it up later.
（霜月）機密レベル３(スリー)の閲覧を
許可します
あとで見ておきなさい
To put it simply,
（花城）簡単に言えば―
it's a special forces unit involved
in the black market and overseas looting.
闇経済や海外での略奪に関わる
極秘の特殊部隊
It's one of the reasons
the current SAD was formed.
今の行動課が生まれた理由の１つよ
I want you to leave them to us.
（狡噛）
連中は俺たちに任せてもらおう
It doesn't feel like it's been lived in.
（六合塚）生活感 ないですね
It's too big for one person.
１人暮らしだと 持て余しちゃって
My father also served in the Ministry.
父も厚生省勤務でした
It's not like that's why I became
an inspector or anything, though.
まあ―
別に それが監視官になった理由
ってわけじゃないんですが
Foxes in the CID?
（灼）刑事課に狐が？
That's baseless.
ハッ 事実無根ですよ
Unit One is tightly knit.
一係の結束は固い
You trust your colleagues, I see.
仲間を信頼しているのね
Yes, of course I do.
はい もちろん
Then why do you always hide
your real feelings?
じゃあ なぜ あなたは
いつも 本心を隠してるの？
はっ… うう
There's a fox in the CID.
（花城）狐が刑事課にいる
We have intel to that effect.
そんな情報があるわ
I have the report.
（霜月）報告は受けています
She fell into a trap.
She didn't betray us.
わなに はまっただけで
裏切ったわけではない
She'll even help us find Koichi Azusawa.
むしろ 梓澤廣一の捜索に役立つ
Is it safe to trust her?
信じて大丈夫なのか？
Public Safety will bear
the responsibility.
公安局が 全責任を負います
No, I trusted her.
The responsibility is mine.
いえ 彼女を信じた俺が責任を
（霜月）ううっ！
You can't take it all on yourself, Kei.
炯 １人で
背負えるもんじゃないだろ
It's my job. I'll do it.
俺の仕事だ 俺がやる
What's with you?
何だよ それ
Hey, don't fight over it.
おいおい もめるなよ
We'll take her off the scene
if issues arise.
（霜月）支障が出るなら
現場から外すだけよ
Then we'll handle Peacebreaker.
You guard the governor.
（花城）
では ピースブレイカーはうち―
都知事護衛は そっち
We'll also take Koichi Azusawa.
で 梓澤廣一も うちね
What?! In your dreams!
（霜月）ああん？
寝言は寝て言え！
In that case,
the early bird catches the worm.
その態度なら
早い者勝ちになるかも
Fine by me.
うっ それで結構
（花城）フッ では また
Until next time.
That's the extent of Kisaragi's
involvement with the foxes.
（炯）以上が
如月が参加した狐の概略だ
And she's not responsible
for the accident?
（入江(いりえ)）例の事故にも 責任はない
She's not.
It'd be impossible to prove, anyway.
そうよ 実証するのは不可能だし
Well, at least she said something
before things got really bad.
（天馬(てんま)）いいんじゃねえか？
マジで やばくなる前に話したんだ
But she'll be dead in the water
if she doesn't speak up sooner next time.
まあ 次は もっと早く相談しねえと
半殺しだがな
I'm sorry.
（如月）ごめんなさい
（入江）んん…
Anyway, now we can start our fox hunt.
（霜月）とにかく これで
狐狩りを始められるわ
We'll secure Governor Komiya
and lay a trap for Koichi Azusawa.
小宮(こみや)都知事を保護し―
梓澤廣一に わなを張る
Meaning?
（雛河(ひなかわ)）具体的には？
Kisaragi will contact Azusawa
and lure him out.
（灼）如月さんが
梓澤に連絡し おびき出します
You're going to make Kisaragi act as bait?
（入江）わなの餌
如月に やらせるのか？
Yes. We have to fool him.
（灼）はい 確実に だまさないと
You'll make her confront him in person?
（炯）
お前 本人に対じさせる気か？
Any half-measures taken
against a mastermind will backfire.
（灼）主犯相手に
中途半端な作戦は逆効果だよ
はっ
So your plan's airtight, then?!
お前の作戦なら完璧なのか！
んっ…
That's enough!
（霜月）そこまで
Enforcer Kisaragi will contact Azusawa.
如月執行官が梓澤に連絡
Take no further dangerous action.
Dismissed.
その後の危険な行為は なし
以上 解散
There could still be foxes
in the Public Safety Bureau.
（天馬）公安局内に
まだ狐がいるかもしれねえ
Are they fighting?
（天馬）同時にあぶり出さねえとな
（志恩(しおん)）んー？　ケンカ中？
It's about Inspector Ignatov's wife.
イグナトフ監視官の奥さんの件でね
（雛河の力み声）
（足音）
（雛河）あっ
You almost never ask me to meet you.
呼び出すなんて 珍しいですね
What's this?
何ですか？　これ
The data I've gathered on your behavior.
あなたの行動を調べたデータです
あっ
It's the original.
オリジナルです
You can destroy it.
破棄してかまいません
So, you suspected me?
私を疑ってたんですね
My role is to protect Unit One.
自分の役割は 一係を守ること―
That's why.
だからね
That's my role, too.
それは 私も同じです
Yes, I was glad when Sibyl chose me.
ええ シビュラに選ばれた時は
うれしかったです
I was able to use my skills for peace
このスキルを
平和のために使えるし―
and to feel that I was a good person.
自分は よき人間だと
思うことができた
Justice?
正義ですか？
It must be upheld.
守るべきものです
That's why I live without self-deception.
そのために俺は―
自分にウソは つかない生き方を
しています
National Center for Medical Research
Her release was canceled?
退院 取り消し？
Metropolitan policy? What is all this?
都の方針って 何ですか それは！
We're here to discuss a violent act by an
immigrant Public Safety Bureau inspector.
（アナウンサー）入国者である
公安局監視官の暴力行為が―
問題になっています
During the gubernatorial election,
this inspector
先の都知事選で
問題の監視官は―
struck a supporter of Candidate Yakushiji,
causing his Hue to deteriorate.
薬師寺(やくしじ)候補の
支持者を殴り―
色相を
悪化させたとのことです
Yes. He punched me for no reason at all.
（一童）
はい 何の理由もなく
殴られました
To be honest,
I thought he was going to kill me.
正直 殺されるかと
思いましたよ
A rise in immigrant violence
has been my worst fear.
（カリナ）入国者による
暴力事件増加は―
最も恐れていたことです
My government will take strong measures
to halt the spread of Hue deterioration.
色相悪化の拡散を防ぐため―
都として
厳格に対応してまいります
We also have testimony that,
during the transport drone crash,
（アナウンサー）
問題の監視官は―
輸送ドローン墜落事故の際も―
the inspector in question
threatened people with a Dominator.
人々に
ドミネーターを向け―
脅迫行為に
及んだという証言もあり
はっ
This came in handy.
（小畑(おばた)）これ 役に立った
You can have it. It was Torri's, anyway.
（梓澤）あげるよ トーリ君のだし
Useful even after death.
No wonder he was loved by God.
死んでも役に立つとは―
さすが 神に愛された男
Why can't you let an AI
handle this crap?
こんな クソ仕事
人工知能にやらせな
A little false reporting is all it takes
to get this bogus story trending.
ちょっとゆがんだ情報を
与えるだけで―
あんなクソニュース
いくらでもバズる
You're talkative today. All fired up?
（梓澤）
今日は しゃべるね
燃えてきた？
I got promoted to Eleven, thanks to you.
（小畑）
てめえのおかげで
イレブンまで上がった
We'll have to celebrate.
今度 お祝いしなきゃ
How about I kill you, scumbag?
（小畑）殺されたいのか クズ
Hey, what's that?
ねえ それ 何？
A banned book.
（梓澤）発禁本
Hoffmann's
"The Nutcracker and the Mouse King."
ホフマンの
「くるみ割り人形とねずみの王様」
Is it any good?
面白いの？
I like the fight scenes.
（梓澤）戦争シーンが いいんだよ
The nutcracker is a soldier
who battles evil mice.
くるみ割り人形は
悪いねずみと戦う兵士
To rescue a princess,
made hideous by magic,
魔法で醜い姿にされた姫を
助けるため―
he needs to crack the world's hardest nut,
Crackatook.
世界一硬い クラカトゥクくるみを
かち割らなきゃいけない
What do you think Crackatook
is a metaphor for?
クラカトゥクは
何のメタファーだと思う？
Your balls.
（小畑）あんたの金玉
（梓澤）ブフッ 最高 小畑ちゃん
You're the best, Obata.
I love you. Seriously.
マジで愛してる
Shut up.
うるせえ
Right now, the Public Safety Bureau
is my Crackatook.
公安局が 今の俺のクラカトゥクさ
Especially Shindo. He's Atsushi's son.
特に慎導君は篤志さんの息子だ
I've got to crack him
before he becomes like his father.
父親みたいになる前に
かち割ってあげないとね
I am Karina Komiya, Governor of Tokyo.
（カリナ）
東京都知事の小宮カリナです
Yes, we've met.
（灼）知ってます
Welcome to Public Safety, Governor Komiya.
（霜月）
公安局へ ようこそ 小宮都知事
Thank you for taking our request.
了承してくださり
ありがとうございます
I'll be in your care for a little while.
（カリナ）しばらく
こちらで お世話になります
Please wait.
（三森(みつもり)）お待ちください
（霜月）おお？
And you are?
あなたは？
Vice-Governor Mitsumori.
（三森）副知事の三森です
I oversee immigrant policy.
入国者政策担当です
I see...
はあ
I ask you to refrain from assigning
immigrants to her detail.
（三森）入国者を護衛につけるのは
やめてほしい
なっ
Isn't he the one who was on the news?
しかも 彼 報道された人物でしょ？
His wife is a latent criminal.
奥さんは潜在犯だとか？
She is not a latent criminal!
妻は潜在犯じゃない！
You just won't let her be released!
お前たちのせいで
出られないだけだ！
You should know this is a difficult
time due to immigrant-related incidents.
入国者関連の事件で―
今が難しい時期なのは
監視官なら分かるでしょ
くっ
You need to realize that your attitude
will only make matters worse.
（カリナ）
それに あなたのその態度が―
問題を大きくすると気づきなさい
What was that?!
何だと！
Stop, Kei.
（灼）やめろ 炯
Are you on her side?!
お前は都知事の味方か！
Stop this, Inspector Ignatov.
やめなさい イグナトフ監視官
Stand by.
待機を命じます
Yes, ma'am.
はい
Yes, I was irritated at being removed
from the security detail,
（炯）
護衛から外されたことには―
確かに いらだちを覚えました
but it worked out for the best.
でも 結果的に いい状況になれた
Now I can focus on the hunt.
これで 狩りに集中できる
I can't ignore the governor's requests.
（霜月）都知事側の要請は
無視できないわ
So, a political decision, huh?
（天馬）政治的な判断か
You just gotta swallow this pill,
Inspector Ignatov.
つらいが納得するしかねえよ
イグナトフ監視官
I want you
to remove Enforcer Todoroki as well.
なお 廿六木(とどろき)執行官にも
外れてもらう
What?! How can I go along with that?
（天馬）何だよ そりゃ
納得できるか
Inspector Ignatov, Todoroki, and Kisaragi
will handle the fox hunt.
イグナトフ監視官と廿六木
如月は狐狩りを担当
Inspector Shindo, Irie, and Hinakawa
will protect the governor. Understood?
慎導監視官 入江 雛河で
都知事を護衛 いい？
（天馬）ハァ… 了解
Yes, ma'am.
Can't Inspector Shindo protect
the governor on his own?
都知事の護衛は
慎導監視官１人で十分でしょう
The governor dislikes enforcers.
都知事は執行官を嫌ってます
Isn't that what the enemy wants?
それが敵の狙いなら？
They could use bias against immigrants
and latent criminals to isolate her.
入国者や潜在犯への差別を
利用して―
都知事を孤立させる気かも
Why don't you control the people who think
politics means spreading discrimination?
（炯）
なら 差別をまき散らすことを
政治だと思ってる連中を―
お前が誘導しろ
Isn't manipulation your specialty?!
人の心を操るのは得意だろ
なっ… ん…
Personnel only. No admittance.
I'm grateful to the inspector
for hitting my brother.
（天馬）監視官が
弟を殴ってくれたことに―
俺は感謝してる
All of us here are hopelessly human.
ここの連中はさ
どうしようもなく生身なんだよ
We can't control our anger,
and we say sorry if something goes wrong.
怒りは抑えないし
何かありゃ 悪かったと謝るしよ
Sibyl wouldn't approve,
but it's a perk of this place.
そんな 非シビュラ的な関係が
ここのいいとこだ
I'm sure you understand.
あんたなら分かるだろ
Justice?
正義？
ハァ… 分からんね
I'm not sure.
I mean, it's kind of
an embarrassing word to say,
でも まあ
こっ恥ずかしい言葉だが―
but those who use it in earnest,
really shine.
本気で言ってるやつは
輝いて見えるもんよ
How much can mental tracing
control someone?
メンタルトレースは
どこまで人を誘導できるんだ？
It's more effective than some counseling.
下手なカウンセリングよりは
効果あるよ
It's called psychic driving.
精神誘導 サイキック･
ドライビングっていうんだけど
What about your father?
親父さんは どうだった？
はっ
Kei... are you...?
炯… お前
I don't know what you're thinking, but...
何を思ってるか知らないけど…
Have you ever "driven" me or Maiko?
（炯）お前 俺や舞子(まいこ)を
誘導したことはあるか？
（灼）えっ あ？
No. I haven't. I would never.
ない！　ないよ！　絶対にしない！
I've never done it for myself.
自分のために やったことはないよ
Mentalist, heal thyself.
（炯）人より
自分のメンタルケアをするんだな
I've heard your songs.
（入江）あんたの曲
聴いたことありますよ
They're all pretty good.
どれも悪くない
Thank you.
（六合塚）ありがと
I'd like to hear what you think of
an idol-politician like Karina Komiya.
小宮カリナみたいな
アイドル政治家について―
あんたの意見が聞きたいんだが
The people and Sibyl wanted her.
Nothing more, nothing less.
（六合塚）国民とシビュラが求めた
それ以上でも それ以下でもないわ
The old you would have recorded
a bunch of dis tracks against her.
昔のあんたなら都知事をディスって
何曲か作ったでしょう
Hey, don't forget
that you're the one being interviewed.
（六合塚）ねえ これは
あなたのインタビューよ
忘れないで
Justice, huh?
フハハッ 正義ねえ…
It's a word losers shout a lot.
負け犬が よく吐く言葉だろ
My dad died believing in that word.
俺の親父も その言葉を信じ―
死んじまったよ
This may be indiscreet of me,
but I guess I'm glad to see you again.
（カリナ）
こんな時に不謹慎だけど―
また あなたに会えて楽しいかも
（灼）ハハッ
I feel a little bit better
to hear you say so.
そう言ってもらえると
少し気が楽です
I'm sorry about your partner.
It's my fault.
（カリナ）ごめんなさい
相棒さんの件 私のせいね
That's not entirely true.
そう一概には言えないでしょ
Are you scared of something?
何か怖がってる？
What do you mean?
何です？　それ
You used to be more carefree.
（カリナ）以前の余裕がないから
I'm a bit busy.
ハァ… ちょっと忙しくて
By the way, where's your first secretary?
そういえば 第１秘書の女性は？
I laid En off.
アンは… 解雇したの
What?
Party policy.
（灼）えっ？
（カリナ）党の方針
I couldn't keep En at my side,
all because of that.
そんなもののせいで アンを
そばに置くことができなかった
Just like your partner.
あなたの相棒と同じよ
Politics is the one way to reduce violence
and minimize conflict.
政治は暴力を和らげ―
争いを最小化する唯一の手段
That's why I'm a politician.
だから 政治家になった
I'll make this a country
where no one can complain
私は 私の隣にアンがいても―
even if En or your partner
were at my side.
あなたの相棒がいても―
誰にも文句を言わせない国に
してみせる
That's admirable.
立派です
What's gotten into you?
（カリナ）何よ それ
I can understand your position
and beliefs.
（灼）あなたの立場も信念も
理解できる
And I have a request.
その上で お願いが
Please release my partner's wife.
相棒の奥さんを解放してください
I'll do what I can.
努力するわ
In exchange, make sure you keep me safe.
そのかわり
私をしっかり守ってよね
Mao's fake security schedule
is on the Public Safety Bureau
（志恩）真緒(まお)ちゃんの
偽の護衛スケジュールを―
公安局 それと
都の政策局のサーバーに入力済みよ
and Metropolitan Policy Bureau servers.
Then the enemy will see
how convenient Kisaragi is.
敵は如月の便利さに
気づくってわけだ
Will they notice?
気づくでしょうか
Let's trust the enemy's competence.
（炯）敵の優秀さを信じよう
I owe my life to Inspector Ignatov
and his wife.
（如月）イグナトフ監視官と
奥さんに 命を救われました
The inspector is a strong-willed person,
worthy of respect.
監視官は強い意志を持った
尊敬すべき方です
You seem like a strong person yourself.
（六合塚）
あなたも 強い人間に見えますよ
I'm not.
いいえ 事件があると―
Every time a crime occurs,
I'm reminded of how weak I am.
いつも 自分の弱さを
思い知らされます
Risking our lives to protect others.
命懸けで他人を守る
I've realized recently
that that's what justice means for us.
それが私たちの正義だと
最近 気づきました
Enforcer Kisaragi Mao
はっ
It's here.
来ました
I guess that's about it for the case.
事件に関しては そんなとこかな
Should you really tell all this
to an outsider?
いいの？　部外者に話して
I know you know what's safe to air
and what isn't.
報道していいことと
まずいことの区別は分かるでしょ？
My Crime Coefficient
has been dropping lately, too.
最近 私もね
犯罪係数 下がってるんだ
I thought I'd spend my whole life here.
一生 ここで暮らすんだと思ってた
Ever heard this story?
こんな話 知ってる？
A species of lizard was chased
into the trees by an invasive species.
あるトカゲの種は
外来種によって木の上に追われた
After 15 years, the lizards' bodies
had adapted to cling to trees,
15年が たった時―
トカゲの体は
木に くっつくように適応してた
and they couldn't go back to the ground.
そして 地上に戻れなくなった
You're not a lizard.
あなたはトカゲじゃない
ハァ… フッ
You've always wanted to be a congressman,
haven't you?
（代銀(しろがね)）君は ずっと
コングレスマン志望だね
Due to my unfortunate upbringing.
（梓澤）不幸な生い立ちのせいです
It was a tragic drama...
そこには とても悲しいドラマが
That's not the story I know.
（代銀）私が知る話と違うな
Nothing gets past you.
I don't remember my childhood.
（梓澤）さすが
子供の頃なんて 覚えてません
My trauma comes from
my Ministry of Welfare days.
根深いのは
厚生省時代のトラウマです
Atsushi Shindo?
（代銀）慎導篤志か
Yes.
ええ 彼に おとしめられたことで
俺は才能に目覚めた
Being crushed by him awakened my talents.
I hate him,
but he was also my greatest teacher.
彼は
憎むべき相手であると同時に―
最高の師でした
Interesting.
面白い
To be frank, a man of your ability
is worthy of being a congressman.
正直 君ほどの男は
コングレスマンの地位がふさわしい
Just what I wanted to hear!
待ってました！
But there are those
who oppose your appointment.
（代銀）
だが 君の就任を拒む者もいる
That makes it more worthwhile.
（梓澤）より やりがいがあります
There's also Shindo's son.
慎導の息子もいますしね
Arata Shindo is criminally asymptomatic.
（代銀）慎導 灼は免罪体質者
He was born immune to Sibyl's judgment.
生まれつき シビュラにも裁けない
A being equal to Bifrost.
ビフロストに等しい存在だ
What does it mean
to be "criminally asymptomatic"?
一体 何なんです？
免罪体質者って
You'll find out
when you become a congressman.
君もコングレスマンになれば分かる
Tokyo Metropolitan Government Building
I'll check the parking lot, Inspector.
Please stand by.
（入江）監視官 駐車場を
チェックするから待機してくれ
Understood.
（灼）了解です
There sure are a lot
of paparazzi drones out.
それにしても―
パパラッチドローンの数
すごいですね
There have been a lot of cases lately.
（カリナ）
最近 事件が多いせいでしょう
And everyone is oversensitive
when it comes to immigrants.
みんな 入国者には
過剰に反応するから
Shion.
志恩さーん
Yes? What is it?
（志恩）はーい 何？
Please track all nearby drones
and send me the data.
付近のドローン すべて追跡して
データを送ってください
Let me see...
（志恩）えーっと
Hey, that's too many of them!
ちょっと 数多すぎ
As fast as possible, please.
最速で お願いします
What was that about?
（カリナ）さっきのは？
If they set a trap,
they'll put surveillance support in place.
（灼）仕掛けを用意するなら
監視のサポートを置きますよ
That's what I'd do.
俺なら そうする
What you would do?
（カリナ）“俺なら”って…
Do you and the criminal
think so much alike?
そんなに犯人とあなた
考えた方が似てるの？
Of course not.
まさか
His disinterest in humans makes me sick.
こいつの人間への興味のなさには
吐き気がしますよ
He sees a world full of people
大勢が暮らすこの世界を―
as nothing but a gigantic puzzle.
ただの巨大なパズルとしか
思ってない
He treats people as game pieces.
人間をゲームの駒にしてるんだ
People who make the wrong choices
die on their own.
選択を間違えた人間が勝手に死ぬ
His contrivances assure that.
そういう仕組みを作ってる
But you can figure them out, can't you?
でも あなたなら読み解ける
でしょ？
Barely.
必死ですよ
This is an investigation, isn't it?
（雛河）これって
事件の捜査 ですよね？
I mean, you're the only former member
of Unit One with freedom of movement.
だって 自由に動ける元一係は―
先輩だけ
フッ
Everything I know about justice,
I learned in CID Unit One
僕にとっての正義は―
すべて 刑事課一係…
from Inspector Tsunemori.
常守監視官から学びました
I'll go alone
so they don't suspect anything.
怪しまれないよう 俺１人で行く
Without backup? I can't agree to that.
援護なしってのは いただけねえな
I'm against it as well.
私も反対です
Besides,
this used to be Enomiya's headquarters.
それに ここは
榎宮(えのみや)のアジトだった場所
Don't worry.
I'll contact you when I need backup.
大丈夫だ
応援が必要な時は連絡する
What's this about?
（静火(しずか)）話とは何です？
It's about Congressman Shirogane.
（梓澤）コングレスマン 代銀氏に
ついてですよ
He wants to eliminate you.
彼は あなたを
排除しようとしている
And?
それが？
He plans to use me.
俺を使う気です
That sounds like Shirogane.
代銀さんらしい
You're weighing him and me
against each other, I suppose?
あなたは 私と彼を
てんびんにかけているのですね
No. I want to help you.
いいえ あなたの力に
なりたいんですよ
You're like me.
あなたは俺に似ている
That's a misunderstanding.
それは勘違いです
Oh?
あら？
Why do you want to be a congressman?
なぜ コングレスマンに
なりたいのですか？
It's no use dissembling.
建て前は無用です
As long as people live,
they are merely cogs in society's machine.
人は生きているかぎり
社会の中の歯車にすぎない
In which case, I want to be on top.
であれば 俺は その頂点を目指す
I'm glad you answered honestly.
正直に答えてくれて うれしいです
In the sense that we do not place value
on people's humanity,
人間の人間らしさを
重要視していない―
という点において―
we are indeed alike.
確かに 私とあなたは似ている
Then...?
But I don't think of people as cogs.
じゃあ…
（静火）ですが 私は―
人間を歯車とは思わない
And I despise games.
それに ゲームが嫌いだ
But you're so good at them.
（梓澤）とても お強いのに
Preferences have nothing to do with that.
好きか嫌いかは関係ない
I knew I liked you.
俺は やっぱり あなたがいい
I'll show you proof that you need me.
Wait a moment.
俺が必要だという証拠を見せます
少々 お待ちを
（足音）
You're the fox messenger?
I want further instructions.
狐の使いだな？
次の指示が欲しい
I knew this was a setup.
やはり はめられたか
Yes, I knew he was the most dangerous.
（梓澤）うーん
やはり 彼が一番 危険だ
Public Safety Inspector Ignatov,
I presume?
（静火）公安局の
イグナトフ監視官だね？
What?
（炯）何？
I'll be brief.
手短に説明する
I am involved with Bifrost
in an important capacity.
私は ある重要なポジションで
ビフロストに関わっている
あっ
You're not a fox?
狐では ないのか？
No.
（静火）そうだ
そして ある理由から―
And, for certain reasons,
my life is currently in danger.
今 ここで命を狙われている
What do you mean?
（炯）どういうことだ？
Enomiya was a monomaniac.
榎宮… 彼女は偏執狂だった
（スイッチを押す音）
I'm sure they made escape routes.
（静火）必ず逃げ道を作る
あっ
They'll probably send
the two Pathfinders.
（静火）来るとすれば
パスファインダーの２人だ
We can't beat them in a fair fight.
まともに戦って
勝てる相手ではない
（２人）ん？
んっ
Gino!
ギノ！
I want you to protect me. However,
（静火）
私を守ってほしい ただし―
promise that you will not mention me
to anyone.
私の存在を誰にも口外しないと
約束しろ
What are you babbling about?
（炯）何をふざけた話を…
In exchange, I will release your wife.
見返りに 君の奥さんを解放しよう
なっ… どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
Here.
これを
Take this.
受け取れ
If you want to learn the truth from me,
私のもとで真実を知りたいなら―
register your biometrics with the device.
デバイスで
生体認証を登録したまえ
ん…
（衝撃音）
（２人）んっ
（狡噛）うわっ
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs?
Don't let them come in contact with me.
外務省か…
彼らも私に接触させるな
Help me escape from here on your own.
君１人で 私をここから脱出させろ
Who are you?
No time.
（炯）お前は何者な…
（静火）時間がない
Choose.
Cooperate with me or abandon me.
選べ 協力するか 私を見捨てるか
（炯）ん…
Follow me.
ついてこい
うっ くっ…
くっ く… あっ
（アラーム）
Time's up.
（ジャックドー）時間切れだ
We'll kill you next time.
（ヴィクスン）次は 必ず殺す
（通信機の音）
Sorry. They got away.
（狡噛）すまん 逃がした
Both enemies were present?
（花城）敵は ２人ともいたのね？
I confirmed it.
確認した 間違いない やつらだ
There's no doubt. It's them.
You all right, Kogami?
狡噛 無事か？
Yeah. More importantly,
（狡噛）ああ そんなことより―
something bothers me.
気になることがある
Fast work. That's our Shion.
（灼）
さっすが志恩さんは仕事が速い
There are an awful lot of drones.
（雛河）ドローンの数 かなり多い
How do we find the right one?
本命を どう見つける？
Crackers can't help but leave a signature.
（灼）クラッカーは無意識に―
自分のマークを残す
（タイピング音）
We're with Public Safety.
公安局の者です
What?
何？
Please come with us.
（灼）ご同行願います
Crime Coefficient is under 60.
（ドミネーター）
犯罪係数 アンダー60
Not a target for enforcement action.
執行対象ではありません
The trigger will be locked.
トリガーをロックします
She's clean, Inspector.
シロだぜ 監視官
It doesn't matter.
関係ありません
Isn't that a bit...
それは さすがに…
Is this compulsory?
これ 強制なの？
It can be.
Would you like me to get authorization?
強制も可能です
許可を取りましょうか？
Shut up.
Fine, I'll go. Happy?
うっぜえな
行けばいいんだろ 行けば
That was good work.
（静火）いい働きだった
Are you a congressman?
（炯）お前は コングレスマンか？
I'm someone who can give you
what you currently most desire.
（静火）私は―
今 君が一番 願っていることを
かなえられる者だ
Now, make up your mind and choose.
あとは君が決断し 選択しろ
んっ
Are you OK? What happened?
大丈夫か？　何があった！
No problems.
（炯）問題ない
Sorry I didn't contact you.
連絡せず すまなかった
（炯）うっ
What happened in there? Answer me.
あそこで何があった？　答えろ
I simply evacuated a civilian.
一般人を避難させただけだ
More importantly, what about them?
それより あの連中は？
The Peacebreaker remnants fled.
ピースブレイカーの残党は逃げた
Then you're the ones
who let your target get away!
てめえらこそ
ホシを逃がしてんじゃねえか！
You can't cover up a lie
forever, Inspector.
おい 監視官
ウソは すぐにバレるぞ
Stop interfering in our jurisdiction.
こちらの管轄で
口出しは やめてもらおう
I'll file a formal complaint with
your chief for obstructing our operation.
それより そちらの課長に―
我々の作戦を妨げた件で
正式に抗議する
We're leaving.
帰るぞ
Aren't you late?
（代銀）遅かったじゃないか
I ran into trouble.
（静火）
トラブルがありまして
How unfortunate.
それは災難だったね
On with the game.
フッ ゲームを続けましょう
フフッ
You moron!
このバカたれが！
What were you thinking,
acting without your enforcers?!
執行官を待機させての単独行動
何やってんの！
That was too reckless, Kei.
（灼）むちゃしすぎだろ 炯
You too, idiot! What did you bring in
someone with a clear Hue for?!
（霜月）あんたもよ アホ！
クリアな人間を連れてきて
どうしろってのよ！
She came in for voluntary questioning.
任意同行における事情聴取です
Under threat of a forced search?
（霜月）強制捜査で脅し？
Oh, I give up! Get out, both of you!
I don't want to look at you!
ああ もういい！
２人とも出てって
顔も見たくない！
Wait, I need permission to question...
待ってください 聴取の許可を
Get out!
出てけ！
How did it go?
（細呂木）どうだ？
We caught a fox by the tail.
（霜月）狐の尻尾をつかみました
Ms. Chiyo Obata. What a lovely name.
小畑千夜(ちよ)さん かわいい名前ですね
So what?
You planning to make my Hue cloud?
で 色相が濁るよう 誘導する気？
I'm both an inspector and a mentalist.
俺は監視官であり
メンタリストです
I can manipulate you, but I won't.
あなたを誘導できるけど
あえて しない
Your dad would've.
あんたの親父なら やるね
んっ…
Biometrics confirmed.
（ラウンドロビン）生体認証
Thirteenth Inspector registered.
サーティーン･インスペクターを
登録
Kei Mikhail Ignatov
（電子音）
（炯）ん？
Contract signed. Your wife will be
discharged tomorrow. I'll be in touch.
Discharged?
退院…
（玄関のチャイム）
I'm home.
（舞子）ただいま
Maiko!
舞子！
Did you get me out?
（舞子）あなたが出してくれたの？
I didn't do anything.
（炯）俺は何も
This is only natural.
こうなるのが当然なんだ
Are your eyes all right?
（炯）目は大丈夫か？
They say the surgery was a success.
手術に問題は ないって
I'll be able to see once I settle down.
落ち着いたら きっと見えるって
I'll brew tea and make dinner.
（炯）紅茶でも入れよう
晩飯は俺が作る
Let me. It's been so long.
久しぶりに お料理したい
Let's cook together, then.
（炯）なら 一緒に作ろう
You've made a series of blunders, First.
（代銀）
不手際続きだな ファースト
Not at all.
They were all calculated opening moves.
いえいえ
すべて計算どおりの布石です
Was adding a new inspector part your plan
as well?
では インスペクターが
増えたのも―
君の計画の１つかね？
Shizuka enlisted him as your rival.
えっ？
静火君が
君の対抗馬として擁立した
Well, now.
（梓澤）へえー
Don't falter in the endgame.
詰めをしくじるなよ
Don't worry.
ご安心を
This is where the real game begins.
ここからが本番です
Yeah. Not bad.
うん 悪くない
Thank goodness
they let you out, Mai.
（灼）
舞(まい)ちゃん 出られたんだ よかった
Listen, I heard you had a fight with Kei.
ねえ 炯と もめたって聞いたよ
Oh, yeah...
（灼）ああ うん…
He's sorry for getting too angry.
あの人 怒りすぎたって
反省してる
It was because I failed to protect you.
俺が 君を守れなかったから
What are you both afraid of?
（舞子）
２人で 何を怖がってるの？
ん？
Are we afraid of something?
怖がってるのかな？　俺たち
Neither of you is prepared.
（舞子）２人とも
覚悟ができてないのよ
（灼）ハハッ 舞ちゃんは強いな
You're strong, Mai.
I'm not prepared to see this world,
either.
私も この世界を見る覚悟が
できてない
But I'll be able to see it one day.
でも 必ず見えるようになる
After all,
it's not the world itself that scares us.
だって 怖いのは
この世界そのものじゃなくて―
It's the thought
of losing our bonds, right?
私たちが 絆を失うことじゃない？
Yeah. I think you're right.
（灼）うん そのとおりだと思う
So, Kei hit you, right?
（舞子）
ねえ 炯が殴ったんでしょ？
You can hit him back, OK?
いいのよ 殴り返したって
フッ いいね
Good idea.
Then I'll apologize to Kei.
それから 炯に謝る
Your girlfriend?
（カリナ）今のって彼女？
No.
うわっ！　違うよ
My best friend's wife.
親友の奥さん
フッ
Cologne?
香水？　俺に？
For me?
Having a nice scent on hand when
you're busy is good for your Hue, right?
忙しい時でも香りを整えておくと
色相にいいでしょ
Thank you.
ありがとう
何から何まで お世話になって
You take care of everything for me.
I should be the one thanking you.
こっちのセリフよ ありがと
（灼）フッ
You seem healthy.
（狡噛）元気そうだな
Yes.
はい 体は
昔から丈夫なんですよ 私
I've always been physically tough.
Everyone's the same as ever.
みんなも相変わらずだ
I see.
（朱）そうですか…
Your conviction was right.
（狡噛）あんたの信念は正しかった
You'll be able to say so proudly one day.
胸を張って そう言える日は
必ず来る
Please tell me about yourself sometime,
too.
いずれ 狡噛さんの話も
聞かせてください
Sure. I've got stories from my long trip.
ああ 長い旅の土産話がある
CID Unit One's current investigations
and the last case I was involved in
今の刑事課一係の捜査と
私が関わった最後の事件
are all connected. I'm sure of it.
きっと すべてがつながっている
I honestly don't know
what justice means to me personally.
（灼）僕自身の正義が何なのか―
正直 分かりません
But I can't control the truth.
ただ 真実はコントロールできない
The control of justice...
正義のコントロール
Dad,
（灼）父さん…
I won't run from the truth,
過ちを犯さないために―
so that I won't go wrong.
俺は真実から逃げない
Isn't that right,
そうだろ？
Kei?
炯…
♪～
Stupid perfection in your own castle
How smart. You cause me to yawn
Look,
The key to the door is in your hand
Don't you let anyone take control
What do you want?
Go get it. Play by your own rule
The winner always controls the game
You stand in your belief
There's no promising future
Always helpless
Crying for the moon
Finger trembles in fear
With the weight of the trigger
There's a way for us
Show them how we fight
Pull the trigger
～♪
（クラクション）
（うめき声）
So long to the legendary lady detective.
（梓澤）さらば 伝説の女デカ
"Psycho-Pass" refers to the measurement
of a person's mind and personality.
This is a work of fiction. Any resemblance
to real persons or groups is coincidental.